https://um.dk/en/about-us/organisation/contact-information/the-ministry-of-foreign-affairs-of-denmark-personal-data-policy/

Skip to content
Travel and ResidenceTravel and ResidenceCoronavirus/covid-19How to apply for a visaHow to apply for a residence permitWhere to apply for a visa or residence permitHow to apply for a Danish passportPayment for ServicesNewsLegalisation (Apostille)Legalisation (Apostille)Legalisation of Danish documentsLegalisation of Danish documentsGeneral informationGeneral informationWebshop guideCertificates of birth, baptism, person and nameCertificates of residence and civil statusDeath certificatesEducational documents and diplomasExport documentsMedical certificates & pill passportsPower of attorneysPrivate criminal recordsTranscripts from the Danish Business AuthorityTranslationsTrue copies of private documents (passport, driver’s license, etc.)Legalisation of foreign documentsBrexitFamily and legal issuesFamily and legal issuesForeign citizens' acquisition of real property in DenmarkForeign PolicyForeign PolicyDenmark's Candidate for Secretary-General of the OECDNew Global Climate Action StrategyAfrican-Nordic MeetingP4G - Partnering for Green Growth and the Global Goals 2030Ukraine Reform ConferenceUkraine Reform ConferenceThe Conference in Copenhagen 2018GalleryDenmark in UkraineFamily photoPublicationsLivestreamUkraine-seminar in Bruxelles on 28 May 2018Warm-up to the ConferenceCivil society forum in Kyiv on 14 June 2018The Danish Foreign Minister's visit in UkraineThe Danish chairmanship of the Committee of Ministers of the Council of Europe 2017-2018Nordic and Nordic-Baltic cooperationBaltic Sea CooperationCounter-PiracyThe ArcticThe ArcticGreenland and The Faroe IslandsGreenland and The Faroe IslandsThule Air BaseBusiness Financing in the ArcticDenmark in the EUInternational trade policyGreenland and The Faroe IslandsGreenland and The Faroe IslandsThule Air BaseDanish Defence and Diplomacy in Times of ChangeOffice of the Special Representative for Freedom of Religions or BeliefOffice of the Special Representative for Freedom of Religions or BeliefMinister for Development Cooperation confirms strategy for the Danish FoRB-initiative with small adjustments
News and activitiesDanish Forum for Freedom of Religion or BeliefWeb-conference on Covid-19 and Freedom of Religion or BeliefReport - The International Promotion of Freedom of Religion or BeliefReport - Unlocking the Potential of Interreligious Dialogues for Sustainable DevelopmentReport - Promoting Freedom of Religion or Belief in the Context of Sustainable Development GoalsFuture Foreign ServiceDanidaDanidaDenmarks efforts against COVID-19 in developing countriesSustainable GrowthSustainable GrowthJobs and skillsThe SDGs and Business OpportunitiesFinancing for developmentFinancing for developmentDifferent types of advice and financingCasePartnershipsPartnershipsDanida Market Development PartnershipsDanida Innovation & Business ExplorerDanida Business ExplorerInternational cooperationP4G - Partnering for Green Growth and the Global Goals 2030Strategic Sector CooperationStrategic Sector CooperationSector counsellorsList of Strategic Sector Cooperation projectsCasesProcurementStrategies and prioritiesStrategies and prioritiesPriorities of the Danish Government for Danish Development AssistanceThe UN Sustainable Development GoalsStrategic frameworksStrategic frameworksDenmark's participation in the EU development cooperationDenmark's participation in the EU development cooperationThe EU dressed for a new world orderIntroductionA common agendaA common agendaThe EU as a global force for human rightsThe EU as a stable partner in fragile statesJoint approaches and instrumentsJoint approaches and instrumentsShared results through coherent policiesJoint analyses and programmingBudget support, ownership and accountabilityCommon ground in the multilateral cooperationEU development cooperation and the Danish general publicImplementation of the strategic frameworkAnnex 1: GlossaryAnnex 2: If you would like to know moreDanish Arab Partnership ProgrammeNatural Resources, Energy and ClimateGrowth and EmploymentCountry policiesCountry policiesAfghanistanBangladeshBurkina FasoBurkina FasoIntroductionKey challenges, opportunities and risks in Burkina FasoThe Partnership PolicyStrategic Focus AreasSynergy between instruments (cases)Annex 1 - Key economic dataAnnex 2 - Denmark's development activities in Burkina FasoAnnex 3 - The Burkina Faso Strategy for Accelerated Growth and Sustainable Development Annex 4 - progress towards the MDGs in Burkina FasoGhanaGhanaAnnex 1: Key economic and social dataAnnex 2: Denmark's bilateral development cooperation with GhanaAnnex 3: Overview of progress towards the MDGs in GhanaAnnex 4: Targets from the Medium-Term National Development Policy FrameworkAnnex 5: Danish CSOs working in Ghana and their partnersThe vision: a transformed Ghana - a new strategic partnershipThe national settingThe strategic objectivesKenyaMaliMaliIntroduction: Mali - The Security and Development NexusThe vision: A Stable Mali Enjoying Sustainable Peace and Economic GrowthDenmark in Mali - Instruments, Key Partners and ResultsNational ContextStrategic Objectives for Denmark's Partnership with MaliRisks and ScenariosMonitoring and EvaluationMyanmarNigerSomaliaTanzaniaTanzaniaDenmark and TanzaniaCurrent and future challenges and opportunities in TanzaniaOverall Strategic Objectives and the Danish Focus Areas for CooperationIncreasing Cultural Cooperation and ExchangeResearch and Monitoring of ProgressAnnex 1 - Facts On TanzaniaAnnex 2 - Denmarks Development Activities in TanzaniaAnnex 3 - Overview Of Progress Towards the MDGS In TanzaniaTechnology in DevelopmentCountries and regionsCountries and regionsCooperation with countries and regionsCooperation with countries and regionsAfricaAsiaLatin AmericaThe Middle East and North AfricaEU's Eastern Neighbours EU's Eastern Neighbours EU TwinningContactPartnersPartnersCivil Society OrganisationsCivil Society OrganisationsAdministrative guidelinesHumanitarian OrganisationsHumanitarian OrganisationsDanish Humanitarian OrganisationsDanish Humanitarian OrganisationsThe Humanitarian Contact GroupInternational Humanitarian OrganisationsEUOther MinistriesResearch Organisations and Think TanksInternational OrganisationsInternational OrganisationsOECD/DACThe European UnionGEFResultsResultsEvaluation of development assistanceEvaluation of development assistanceAbout evaluationsEvaluation programmesOngoing evaluationsEvaluation reports and other publicationsEvaluation reports and other publicationsEvaluation reportsEvaluation studiesOther reportsRelevant documentsAbout the Evaluation DepartmentResults and transparencyResults based managementRisk ManagementResults of our workResults of our workNiger: Human rights in the police academy curriculum strengthens trust in the policeEthiopia: Yoghurt enhance poor farmers’ income and delivers improved nutritionEthiopia: Supporting women and girls survivors of violenceFrom Nordhavn to Niger: A school-in-a-boxIndonesia: improved waste managementAbout DanidaAbout DanidaDanida transparencyDanida transparencyParticipate in public consultationsParticipate in public consultationsPrevious consultationsView Danida documentsView Danida documentsCouncil for Development PolicyCouncil for Development PolicyUpcoming Council MeetingsPrevious Council meetingsGrants below DKK 39 millionDanida Grant Committee (closed)Danida Grant Committee (closed)Grant Committee (closed)Previous Grant Committee MeetingsSend feedback to DanidaSend feedback to DanidaAbout Danida FeedbackAnti-CorruptionAnti-CorruptionAbout reporting corruptionReport CorruptionAccess data from programmes and projectsHistoryLegal FrameworkThe Trade CouncilAbout usAbout usThe MinistersThe MinistersThe Minister for Foreign AffairsThe Minister for Foreign AffairsCVMinister for Development Cooperation and Minister for Nordic CooperationMinister for Development Cooperation and Minister for Nordic CooperationCVSpeeches and articles by former MinistersSpeeches and articles by former MinistersSpeeches and articles by Martin LidegaardSpeeches and articles by Mogens JensenSpeeches and articles by Rasmus HelvegSpeeches and articles by Kristian JensenSpeeches and articles by Manu SareenSpeeches and articles by Pia Olsen DyhrSpeeches and articles by Nicolai WammenSpeeches and articles by Christian Friis BachSpeeches and articles by former Foreign MinistersOrganisationOrganisationWhistleblowerSenior ManagementSenior ManagementPermanent Secretary of State Lart Gert LoseState Secretary for Foreign Policy Jesper Moller SorensenState Secretary Trine Rask ThygesenState Secretary Steen HommelState Secretary Erik Brøgger RasmussenState Secretary Carsten Grønbech-JensenContact informationContact informationPress contactsPrivacy NoticePrivacy NoticeThe Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Denmarks Cookie PolicyFind The Danish MFAOrganisation chartThe Danish Foreign ServiceLegal framework for the MFAReporting possible misconductFind us abroadFind us on social mediaFind us on social mediaCode de conduiteCodigo de conductaVerhaltenskodex für soziale MedienCode of conductInternational Press CentreIt Strategy 2013-2016EU tendersCookies on Ministry websitesPartnerMFAPartnerMFAPosting abroadPosting abroadCarHousing conditions in DenmarkHousing conditions on the postRemoval of furniture/household effectsInsurancesPartner and childrenPassport, Danish National Register and voting rightsTravel to the postHealthFinancesLiving conditionsReturning to Denmark from a posting abroadReturning to Denmark from a posting abroadRelocation allowanceTravel to DenmarkPet animalsHealth checkInsuranceDanish National RegisterRemoval of furniture/household effectsChildren's schoolingChildren and youth allowanceCarAdvice and servicesAdvice and servicesPre-departure counsellingServices during the postingServices during the postingMeet2TalkLanguage trainingThe Protocol DepartmentThe Protocol DepartmentProtocol DepartmentProtocol DepartmentVisiting SectionOutgoing State VisitsCross Cutting TasksDiplomatic SectionNewsNewsNewslistCircular NotesThe Vienna ConventionsStandard forms for diplomats etc.Honorary Consuls in the Kingdom of DenmarkThe MFA sustainability initiativeEconomy and resultsEconomy and resultsAnti-corruption policyAnti-corruption policyReporting possible misconductBank details (SKB) of MFA in DenmarkE-learningE-learningAnti-corruptionGender equalityHRBA and the human rights frameworkIntroduction to development cooperationIntroduction to the human rights-based approachIntroduction to DanidaIntroduction to Green GrowthIntroduction to public financial managementProcurement and aid effectivenessWorking for DenmarkOnline DanishOnline DanishLesson 1 On the PhoneLesson 2 At the EmbassyLesson 3 During the Coffee BreakLesson 4 At the Embassy - BorgerserviceLesson 5 The EmbassyLesson 6 Weekend PlansLesson 7 Tell About YourselfLesson 8 At WorkLesson 9 Can I Leave a MessageLesson 10 How do You Like Working HereLesson 11 Welcome to the EmbassyLesson 12 Hello Pleased to Meet YouProcurementProcurementDanida ContractsDanida ContractsNewsContracts with an estimated value up to DKK 1,036,259Contracts with an estimated value up to DKK 1,036,259Contract opportunitiesContracts awarded by DanidaContracts with an estimated value above DKK 1,036,259Contracts with an estimated value above DKK 1,036,259Contract Opportunities
Ministry of Foreign Affairs of DenmarkAbout usOrganisationContact informationPrivacy Notice
Contact informationPrivacy NoticeThe Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Denmarks Cookie Policy
Privacy policy
If you visit or communicate with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Ministry will process your personal data in order to carry out our activities as a Danish public authority. This applies, for instance, when you contact the Ministry’s Consular Services department or when you get help from a Danish Mission abroadWhat information?
The Ministry processes the data that you send us. If it is necessary for our case handling, we will procure data from third parties, e.g. through public registries, including the Danish Civil Registration System (CPR), and/or from other public authorities.
The Ministry undertakes a broad range of activities and therefore processes various categories of personal data. For the most part, the Ministry processes ordinary personal data, such as names and contact information. In certain cases, and particularly in consular cases, the Ministry also processes sensitive personal data, including health data.
If you are at premises of the Ministry, you could be filmed by our surveillance cameras. As part of illustrating the Ministry’s everyday work, events, and highlights, we also sometimes take pictures and record films at the Ministry’s premises and at events organised by the Ministry. This mainly encompasses situational and ambience pictures. Pictures and film will be published on our website and on social media, depending on the circumstances (outlets might include the Ministry’s social media profiles, print publications, posters, info screens, newspapers, and television).
If you do not wish to be photographed or filmed, please notify the photographer. In addition, you should consider staying out of situations that are photographed or filmed. If you are mistakenly photographed or filmed and the picture or film is published on our website, you can always request that the Ministry remove it.
When you visit the Ministry’s websites and accept cookies, the Ministry will collect data about you. You can read our cookie policy here.
For how long will the Ministry keep my personal data?
The Ministry will only process your personal data as long as it is necessary for us to carry out our activities and to comply with our obligations as a Danish public authority.
Once the Ministry has completed the processing, your personal data will be deleted or archived in accordance with applicable legislation unless the Ministry is obliged to keep the data due to other rules, e.g. the rules on registration of public records.
Will anybody else receive my personal data?
In certain cases, the Ministry will share your personal data with other public authorities. The Ministry will not share more data than is necessary and will always do so in accordance with the general rules on the sharing of information between public authorities. If we receive a request for access to public administration records in a case containing your personal data, the Ministry is usually obliged to disclose the data unless it is confidential.
In certain justified cases, the Ministry will transfer personal data to partners that may be located abroad. This is to provide the best possible consular assistance, e.g. in connection with hospitalisation or imprisonment abroad, and/or to assist private companies in the areas of exports, innovation, internationalisation, and investment promotion.
Legal basis
As a Danish public authority, the Ministry processes personal data in compliance with a number of general rules which apply to all public authorities, e.g. the rules on the registration of public records and archiving.
In addition to the general rules, specific legislation applies to the Ministry’s activities. This body of legislation is available (in Danish) at lov om Udenrigstjenesten af 13. april 1983 (amended), lov om visse aspekter af Danmarks Eksportråds virke af 31. januar 2001 (amended) and lov om internationalt udviklingssamarbejde, jf. seneste lov af 18. juni 2012.
Your rights
In connection with the Ministry’s processing of personal data, you have the right to:
Request for access to your personal data
Request the rectification of inaccurate personal data
Request that your personal is personal data erased in special cases
Request that the Ministry’s processing is restricted
Object to the Ministry’s otherwise lawful processing
File a complaint with the Danish Data Protection Agency. Complaints must be addressed to: Datatilsynet, Borgergade 28, 5. sal, 1300 København, e-mail: dt@datatilsynet.dk
Formal requirements
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs is the data controller of the processing of personal data described above.
If you have any questions or wish to invoke your rights as described above, please contact the Ministry’s data protection officer at dpo@um.dk.
Share on Facebook
Share on LinkedIn
Share on Twitter
Print
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs uses cookies on the Ministry's website
We use cookies to optimize the user experience and target the content on the website of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Denmark. By clicking ACCEPT you accept the use of cookies from the Ministry and third parties on the website of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
Select SETTINGS to choose which cookies you wish to accept.
Accept
Cookie Summary
About Cookies
Information about the Ministry of Foreign Affairs' use of cookies
We use cookies to optimize the user experience and target the content on the website of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Denmark. The collection of information also helps targeting of relevant content, compile statistics as well as marketing.
The first time you visit the homepage of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, you will see a banner with information about cookies. By clicking the "Accept"-button, you agree that the Ministry of Foreign Affairs and third parties use cookies.
By clicking "Show Settings", you are able to choose which cookies you wish to accept.
Read more about the Ministry of Foreign Affairs' privacy and cookie policy
